<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-06-18T15:30:18-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/atom.xml</id><title type="html">DistributedGov</title><subtitle>Helping public service teams build highly effective remote and telework environments.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">DistributedGov launches to help public service teams build highly effective remote and telework environments</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/distributedgov-launches" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DistributedGov launches to help public service teams build highly effective remote and telework environments" /><published>2020-06-17T08:58:01-07:00</published><updated>2020-06-17T08:58:01-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/distributedgov-launches</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/distributedgov-launches">&lt;p&gt;As civic leaders wrestle with and seriously address the issues of our times — disasters, pandemics, climate change, health and wellness, economic empowerment — distributed government teams are now a necessity to delivering responsive and resilient public services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Launched to help public service teams build and scale highly effective remote and telework environments, &lt;a href=&quot;https://distributedgov.com/&quot;&gt;DistributedGov&lt;/a&gt; (https://distributedgov.com) takes a broad approach to addressing these challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DistributedGov is a full-scale platform of &lt;a href=&quot;/services&quot;&gt;services&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/guide&quot;&gt;resources&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/community&quot;&gt;community&lt;/a&gt; to support public service leaders and team members as remote/telework becomes a standard way for how government operates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DistributedGov provides a topic-based filter so that public service teams can easily find immediately practical remote/telework services and resources:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Communications&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Culture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hiring&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Managing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meetings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Policy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Project management&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Security&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Technology&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Telework&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;services&quot;&gt;Services&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DistributedGov provides comprehensive &lt;a href=&quot;/training&quot;&gt;training&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/coaching&quot;&gt;coaching&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;/consulting&quot;&gt;consulting&lt;/a&gt; services from &lt;a href=&quot;/people&quot;&gt;distributed work experts&lt;/a&gt; with extensive experience working with and for private industry and government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;guide&quot;&gt;Guide&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;/guide&quot;&gt;Distributed Government Guide&lt;/a&gt; provides topic-based guidance on remote/telework best practices, including checklists, tools and resources specific to both government leaders and team members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;help&quot;&gt;Help&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/people&quot;&gt;DistributedGov community leaders&lt;/a&gt; will also respond to direct questions from the community in an ‘ask us anything’ format. Responses are posted to the &lt;a href=&quot;/help&quot;&gt;help section&lt;/a&gt; of the platform. Initial topics addressed include &lt;a href=&quot;/help/zoom-for-government&quot;&gt;Zoom for government&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/help/zoom-security-zoom-bombing&quot;&gt;Zoom and security&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&quot;/help/why-are-they-called-distributed-teams&quot;&gt;new semantics&lt;/a&gt; around the terms “distributed,” “telework” and “remote.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;webinar&quot;&gt;Webinar&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On June 24, DistributedGov will host a free, one-hour webinar, ‘&lt;a href=&quot;/training/introduction-to-effective-telework-in-government&quot;&gt;Distributed Government 101: Introduction to Effective Telework in Government&lt;/a&gt;,’ presented by John O’Duinn, author of “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amzn.com/1732254907&quot;&gt;Distributed Teams: The Art and Practice of Working Together While Physically Apart&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DistributedGov is powered by &lt;a href=&quot;https://civicactions.com/&quot;&gt;CivicActions&lt;/a&gt;, a 100-person digital government services firm that has operated in a fully distributed work environment with no office since its inception, for more than 15 years.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>melindaburgess</name></author><summary type="html">DistributedGov provides services, resources, and community to help government agencies address current issues and build a more resilient future.</summary></entry></feed>